All right, today we're going to crack the code on a really powerful tool in English grammar,
今日は英語文法の強力なツール、受動態について学びます。
the passive voice. And I promise by the end of this you'll see it's not some confusing rule
最後には、これは難しいルールではないとわかります。
to memorize. No, it's actually a kind of superpower that lets you decide who the real hero of your
実際には、文の本当の主人公を決めるスーパーパワーです。
sentences. So let's dive right in. Okay, so take a look at these two sentences. The teacher
さあ、始めましょう。まずこの2つの文を見てください。教師が彼女を褒めた、彼女は教師に褒められた。
praised her and she was praised by the teacher. On the surface they pretty much say the same
表面的にはほぼ同じことを言っていますよね？
don't they? But there's a really important difference here, in the focus.
でも、焦点に重要な違いがあります。
It's like the spotlight shifts from one person to the other.
スポットライトが一人から別の人に移るようなものです。
And that difference really just boils down to one simple question.
その違いは、単純な質問に集約されます。
Who's the hero of the story? In that first sentence, the hero is clearly the teacher.
物語の主人公は誰ですか？最初の文では、主人公は明らかに教師です。
But in the second one, the hero is her.
しかし、2つ目の文では、主人公は彼女です。
The action is exactly the same, but the main character, totally different.
行動は同じですが、主役は全く異なります。
And you know what? That's the whole point.
これが重要なポイントです。
It's all about choosing who or what you want to put in the spotlight.
誰をスポットライトに置くかを選ぶことが大切です。
And the tool that lets you make that choice,
その選択を可能にするツールが、
the thing that lets you change the hero of your sentence,
文の主人公を変えることができるもの、
well, that's what we call the passive voice. So what is it really?
それが受動態と呼ばれるものです。では、受動態とは何でしょうか？
At its heart, the passive voice just means to be done.
受動態の本質は「されること」です。
You hear it all the time, cheese is made, the song was sung.
「チーズは作られる」「歌は歌われた」といった表現です。
See how that works? The structure takes the focus off the person
どう機能するか分かりますか？構造は、
doing the action and puts it right onto the person
行動を行う人から受ける人に焦点を移します。
or thing that's receiving the action.
これで「何」と「なぜ」をカバーしましたが、
So that covers the what and the why,
実際に受動態の文をどう作るのでしょうか？
but how do you actually build one of these sentences yourself?
良いニュースは、思っているよりずっと簡単です。
Well, the good news is it's way simpler than you might think.
基本的な公式があり、それを知れば大丈夫です。
There's a basic formula, and once you know it, you've got it.
見てみましょう。これがその公式です。
Let's take a look. And here it is.
これが全体の秘密のコードです。
This is basically the secret code to the whole thing.
2つの部分から成り立っています。動詞「be」の形、
It's just two little parts, a form of the verb to be, you know,
例えば「is」「are」「was」「were」など、
like is, are, was, or were,
それに過去分詞を加えます。それだけです。
and then you add something called the past participle. That's it.
実際にどう機能するか見てみましょう。
Let's see how this actually works in practice.
現在形では「彼らは英語を話す」と言います。
So in the present tense, we'd say, they speak English.
過去形では「彼らは英語を話した」、簡単ですね。
In the past, they spoke English, simple enough.
でも受動態にするには、
But to make it passive,
特別な動詞の3つ目の形、spokenが必要です。
we need that special third form of the verb, spoken.
それを「is」と組み合わせて、「英語はそこで話される」となります。
We just pair it with is and we get, English is spoken there.
これは非常に重要なので、しっかり理解してください。
Now, this is super important, so I really want this to sink in.
これが人々が陥る最大の罠です。
This is the number one trap people fall into.
「過去分詞」という名前は少し混乱を招きますが、
The name past participle is a little confusing
過去形とは全く関係ありません。
because it has absolutely nothing to do with the past tense.
受動態に必要な特別な動詞の形だと考えてください。
Just think of it as the special verb form
それが重要です。
you need for the passive voice. That's a toll job.
さて、過去分詞を理解することが最も重要なステップです。
Okay, so you can probably see that getting the hang
良いニュースは、これらは2つの明確なグループに分かれます。
of these past participles is the most important step.
規則動詞と不規則動詞です。
And the great news is they basically fall into two very clear groups,
まずは簡単な方から始めましょう。これをレベル1と呼びます。
the regular ones and the irregular ones.
これが規則動詞です。信じてください、
Let's start with the easy stuff, okay? We'll call this level one.
これらは最初に理解するのに最適な友達です。
These are the regular verbs and trust me,
なぜなら、ほとんどの規則動詞は、
they're gonna be your best friend
過去形と過去分詞が全く同じだからです。
when you're just starting to figure this out.
「paint」は「painted」、「washed」は「washed」です。
And here's why they're so easy. For almost all regular verbs,
過去形を知っていれば、過去分詞も知っているということです。
The past tense form and the past participle form are exactly the same.
簡単ですね。
They just end in ed. Paint, painted, painted.
さて、これについてはかなり自信が持てましたか？次のレベルに進みましょう。
Wash, washed, washed. So if you already know the past tense,
ボスレベル、つまり不規則動詞の時間です。でも心配しないでください、
you already know the participle. See? Simple.
彼らは思っているほど怖くありません。これらは、
All right, feeling pretty good about that? Let's level up.
新しい形を覚える必要があるものです。例えば、speak, spoke, spoken。
It's time for the boss level, the irregular verbs. But don't worry,
take, took, taken。break, broke, broken。
But hang on, look closely. Do you see a pattern here?
ちょっと待って、よく見て。パターンが見える？
A lot of these end with that Ian sound.
これらの多くは「イアン」で終わっている。
That's a great little clue to listen for.
これは良い手がかりだね。
So, what's the best way to get these locked into your brain?
これを脳に定着させるにはどうすればいい？
Honestly, the best advice is the simplest. Just practice them.
正直、最もシンプルなアドバイスは練習すること。
Say them out loud. Speak, spoke, spoken. Write, wrote, written.
声に出して言ってみて。speak, spoke, spoken。write, wrote, written。
Write them down a few times.
何度か書いてみて。
that repetition really builds a kind of muscle memory.
その繰り返しが筋肉記憶を育てる。
Okay, let's do a quick practice round. The song is loved.
では、簡単な練習をしよう。歌は「loved」。
Yep, that's a regular one, easy.
そう、これは普通のやつ、簡単だね。
The vase was broken, that's a regular.
「The vase was broken」、これも普通。
How about the photo was taken? And finally, Spanish is spoken.
「The photo was taken」はどう？最後に「Spanish is spoken」。
See, you're already getting the hang of it. Fantastic.
ほら、もうコツをつかんできたね。素晴らしい。
So now you've got the basic building blocks down.
基本的な要素は押さえたね。
Let's add two more essential skills to your toolkit,
次に、2つの重要なスキルを加えよう。
how to make negative sentences, and how to ask questions.
否定文の作り方と質問の仕方だ。
Making a passive sentence negative could not possibly be easier.
受動態の文を否定するのはとても簡単。
Seriously, all you do is find that B verb, in this case it's is,
本当に、B動詞を見つけて、その後に「not」を付けるだけ。
and you just stick the word not right after it. That is it.
それだけでOK。
You don't change anything else.
他は何も変えない。
And asking a question, it's just as simple.
質問をするのも同じくらい簡単。
You take your sentence, you find that same B verb,
文を取り、同じB動詞を見つけて、
and you just move it to the very front of the sentence.
文の最初に移動させる。
English is spoken becomes is English spoken?
「English is spoken」は「Is English spoken?」になる。
The word order is the whole trick.
語順が全てのコツだ。
Answering these questions is a total breeze too.
これらの質問に答えるのも簡単。
You just respond using that same B verb. Is English spoken?
同じB動詞を使って答えるだけ。Is English spoken?
Yes, it is. Is cheese made from milk? No, it isn't.
はい、そうです。Is cheese made from milk? いいえ、違います。
Super simple and direct. Okay, let's pull back for a second
とてもシンプルで直接的だね。さて、少し引いて
and just recap everything we've covered
これまでの内容を振り返ろう。
because you haven't just learned some boring grammar rule.
ただの退屈な文法ルールを学んだわけじゃない。
You've actually gained a new communication superpower.
新しいコミュニケーションのスーパーパワーを手に入れたんだ。
It really all comes down to these four steps.
これらの4つのステップに集約される。
Number one, the formula is always B plus the past participle.
1つ目、公式はB動詞プラス過去分詞。
Number two, get comfortable with the regular
2つ目、規則的と不規則な過去分詞に慣れる。
and irregular participles. Three, to make it negative, just add not.
3つ目、否定するには「not」を加える。
And four, to ask a question, just move the B verb to the front.
4つ目、質問するにはB動詞を前に移動させる。
That's the entire system right there.
これが全体のシステムだ。
And this takes us right back to where we started.
これで最初の話に戻る。
Remember these two sentences?
この2つの文を覚えてる？
Now the difference is perfectly clear, isn't it?
今や違いは明確だね。
One sentence is about John and the other is about Jennifer.
1つはジョンについて、もう1つはジェニファーについて。
You are the one in control of the focus. you get to choose your hero.
焦点をコントロールするのはあなた。ヒーローを選べる。
You've got the keys now. You know how to build these sentences,
今や鍵を手に入れた。文を作る方法がわかる。
how to make them negative, and how to turn them into questions.
否定文の作り方、質問への変換もできる。
So really, there's only one thing left to ask.
だから、最後に聞きたいことがある。
Now that you know the secret,
秘密を知った今、
who's gonna be the hero of your next sentence?
次の文のヒーローは誰になる？